goireland.com 2007-12-29

# Privacy Policy - GoIreland.com

Home About us Privacy Policy  
  
This privacy statement applies to users of the GoIreland.com and Gulliver.ie websites. It also applies where visitors to the GoIreland.com wish to book accommodation, on that site, as the accommodation booking section of the goireland.com website is powered by Gulliver Ireland. We at gorieland.com and gulliver.ie, (each of these websites are referred to here as the "site") are committed to protecting your privacy and this privacy statement sets out the use we make of any of your information that we may obtain by the use of our site. Both the goireland.com site, and the gulliver.ie site are operated by Gulliver InfoRes Services Ltd of FEXCO Centre, Langford Street, Killorglin, Co Kerry, Ireland (referred to here as "we"/"us"/"our"). 

## USE OF THIS SITE

**Using this site**   
By using our site, you signify that you agree with the terms of our current privacy policy as posted on this site. 

**Aggregate Information**   
We collect general information about each individual visitors experience of our website. We collect information such as the Internet Protocol address of persons using the site, browser types, referring pages, pages visited, time spent on the site etc. Individuals cannot be identified by this information and we use it, like cookies (see below) to improve the performance, design and layout of the site, and bringing our customers the type of content and products they want. 

**Cookies**   
Certain sections of the site use cookies to which allow us to track and record user sessions and to recognise you, if you come back to our site. A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enables the server to collect information back from the browser. You have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. 

**Subscribing to our Newsletter**   
The newsletter sign up form allows you to register for our regular newsletters. This means that you will be the first to hear about last minute deals, special offers, discounts and new products and services. We send this newsletter to you by email, and we collect your email address for this purpose. Our email management provider (Constant Contact) processes the sending out of our newsletter. Our email management provider is located in the US, and your email address is transferred outside of Ireland, to them solely to allow them process the sending of the newsletter. If you do not agree to this, please contact our privacy officer, whose details are indicated below. For more information on Constant Contact, see [www.roving.com](http://www.roving.com/)

With each newsletter that we send to you, we provide you a link to this privacy policy and also give you the right to unsubscribe from our email list. We will delete your email address from our list of newsletter subscribers as soon as possible after we receive your unsubscribe notification. 

**External Links**   
This site contains links to other websites, which include, for example, in relation to the goireland.com site, the sections of that website relating to car hire, online tee times, shopping, vacation packages and travel insurance. We cannot be held responsible for the privacy or security practices or the contents of such websites. 

**Contacting Us**   
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, or the security practices of this site, you can contact us by emailing us at [privacy@gulliverireland.com](mailto:privacy@gulliverireland.com), or writing us at the address above. Please mark correspondence "For the Attention of Privacy Officer". Also please contact us if you have any comments on how we can improve our privacy policies. We reserve the right to change or remove this privacy policy at our discretion and will post any new privacy policy here and we encourage you to visit this area frequently to stay informed. 

**Access to or Rectification of Your Information**   
You have the right to obtain a copy of the information that we hold about you. You can also request that we rectify or erase any information that we hold about you, if that information is incorrect. You can obtain information about yourself, or request a rectification or erasure, by writing to the Privacy Officer, GoIreland.com, Langford Street, Killorglin, Co Kerry, or by sending an email to [privacy@gulliverireland.com](mailto:privacy@gulliverireland.com). 

**Irish Data Protection Commissioner**   
Further information on your data privacy rights are available on the website of the Irish Data Protection Commissioner. <http://www.dataprivacy.ie/>

## BOOKING ACCOMMODATION

**Making a booking**   
When making a booking for accommodation on our website we collect your name, address, email address as well as your credit or debit card number and expiry date. We use this information to process your booking. When you book, your information is encrypted and passed through a secure server. We retain this information, for 120 days after your booking, to deal with any queries you or the accommodation owner may have after your stay. 

The information you provide, including your full credit card details, are also made available to the accommodation provider. This is because under our terms and conditions, if a cancellation occurs within specific time periods, the accommodation provider is entitled to deduct from your credit card the full cost of your first nights stay. We request that accommodation providers keep your details secure and private, and not to hold onto your information for a period greater than 120 days from the date of the booking, however, we cannot be held responsible for any accommodation provider’s misuse of personal information. 

We also ask for your telephone number so our customer support representatives and the accommodation provider can contact you if there is a question concerning your reservation. 

**Marketing Information**   
Where you have indicated that we may do so, we use the information that you have provided when making a booking, to inform you of new products or services offered by us, or to supply you with other promotional information. We also, with your consent, provide your details to selected third parties who may also inform you of new offers or promotions. You can contact us at any time where you no longer wish to receive such information. 

**Registered Users**   
By registering with us, you can avail of the added benefits offered through the site. These include being able to cancel your reservation on line and to be able to book sets of accommodation in the one session, so you can create your own itinerary. Also by registration, we will store your information so that the input fields will automatically repopulate when you rebook during another session. We retain your registered information for these purposes. 

## SECURITY

**Security Statement**   
Security remains the primary concern of on-line consumers. The VeriSign Secure Site Program allows you to learn more about web sites you visit before you submit any confidential information. 

We guarantee that every transaction you make with us will be 100% safe. This means you will not be out of pocket if unauthorised charges are made to your credit or debit card as a result of bookings made through us. 

**Our Safe Shopping Guarantee**   
None of our on-line customers have reported fraudulent use of a credit or debit card as a result of a booking through our service. We are confident about the transaction security we offer on this site and back every booking with a security guarantee, as follows:- 

  * Our secure server software encrypts all your personal information including credit or debit card number, name and address. The encryption process takes the characters you enter and converts them into bits of code that are then securely transmitted over the Internet; 
  * In the event of unauthorised use of your credit or debit card, most banks and card issuers either cover all the charges or may limit your liability to just €63; 
  * If your bank or card issuer holds you liable, Gulliver Ireland will cover your liability up to €63 provided that the unauthorised use of your credit or debit card resulted through no fault of your own from bookings made through the site while using the secure server. 

**Additional Points on Security**

  * This guarantee only applies to credit or debit card purchases made using our secure server and not other services that may be available from the goireland.com or gulliver.ie websites; 
  * This guarantee covers a maximum liability of €63. 
  * In the event of unauthorised use of your credit or debit card, you must notify your card provider in accordance with its reporting rules and procedures. 

To give you an additional layer of security, all credit or debit card numbers are stored on a computer that is not connected to the Internet. After you type in your complete card number, it is transferred to this secure machine across a proprietary one-way interface. This computer is not accessible by network or modem and the number is not stored anywhere else
